The untold story behind the miracle on the Hudson.
Sully is a drama, history film directed by Clint Eastwood.
On 15 January 2009, the world witnessed the 'Miracle on the Hudson' when Captain 'Sully' Sullenberger
glided his disabled plane onto the Hudson River, saving the lives of all 155 souls aboard.
However, even as Sully was being heralded by the public and the media for his unprecedented feat of aviation
skill, an investigation was unfolding that threatened to destroy his reputation and career.
Chesley 'Sully' Sullenberger, played by Tom Hanks.
Jeff Skiles, played by Aaron Eckhart.
Elizabeth Davis, played by Anna Gunn.
Mike Cleary, played by Holt McCallany.
Charles Porter, played by Mike O'Malley.
Ben Edwards, played by Jamey Sheridan.
Sully (also known as Sully: Miracle on the Hudson) is a 2016 American biographical drama film directed by Clint Eastwood and written
by Todd Komarnicki, based on the 2009 autobiography Highest Duty by Chesley "Sully" Sullenberger and Jeffrey Zaslow.
Tom Hanks stars as Sullenberger, with Aaron Eckhart as Jeffrey Skiles, and co-stars
Laura Linney, Anna Gunn, Autumn Reeser, Holt McCallany, and Jamey Sheridan.
The film follows Sullenberger's 2009 emergency landing of US Airways Flight 1549 on the Hudson River, in
which all 155 passengers and crew survived, and the subsequent publicity and investigation.
Sully premiered at the 43rd Telluride Film Festival on September 2,
2016, and was released in the United States by Warner Bros.
on September 9, 2016, in conventional and IMAX theaters.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed over $240 million worldwide, but created controversy with its fictionalized portrayal of the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) as "prosecutorial and
closed-minded." The American Film Institute and National Board of Review each selected it as one of their ten best films of 2016, and it was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Sound Editing at the 89th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of rescue, new york city,
airplane, investigation, pilot.
The tone is emotional.